<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: new york | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/new-york/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-07T11:14:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Irving Farm, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-irving-farm/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T20:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-irving-farm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.irvingfarm.com/index.cfm">Irving Farm Coffee Roasters</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, 14th St &amp; 7th Ave, Uptownish<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Irving Farms<br/>
<strong>Machines</strong>: La Marzocco &amp; Doge<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: yes<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: Unknown<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 8oz ceramic cup<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cap<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 9/2/12</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/irvingfarm.jpg"/></p>

<p>Verdict: Noms. Seems like a lot of places in NYC are serving Intelligentsia
coffee.  While I don't object necessarily, it's nice to see a coffee shop using
locally roasted or even better, roasting its own.  My drink was mild and
reminded me a bit of Stumptown with it's citric tinge. They heated the milk
a bit more than some places but it was still drinkable and I like my milk with
a smidge of heat so the drink doesn't cool off too soon. I'm guessing they heat
to 145-150.</p>

<p>There are four small tables and a wall bench at this location, so the lounge
factor isn't high.  However, the was an elderly man enjoying his newspaper
when I got here and so I'm guessing foot traffic isn't too obnoxious.
The shop is small and unassuming from the outside and I wouldn't have noticed
except I got off the subway there and was looking for friends.</p>

<p>Fyi, no public bathroom</p>

<p><strong>Final Word</strong>: Noms.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Financier, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-financier/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T19:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-financier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://financierpastries.com/">Financier Coffee</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, Cedar &amp; William, Downtown, Financial District<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Financier (roasted in Park Slope, Brooklyn)<br/>
<strong>Machine</strong>: La Marzocco &amp; Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: kind of ("It's not working right now") <br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 8oz ceramic cups after I asked twice for "here"<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 9/2/2012</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/financiercoffee.jpg"></p>

<p>This drink had the potential to taste good.  Unfortunately the
barista had no concept of micro foam or craftsmanship. The taste is a little harsh but I can see
that it could taste awesome if prepared correctly.</p>

<p>Financier prepares and roasts their own beans and so I may come back again and
check as it has the advantage of being close to where I'm staying and the
subway stations are totally horked with construction this weekend. (n.b.
I didn't. I walked to Kaffe 1668 in search of a sure thing).</p>

<p>The pasty case looks amazing but I won't be able to report on that. The store
has long bar seating at the window plus some table in the back. While
I prefer the dark hipster coffee shops, this is still ok.  The music is kind
of pop/r&amp;b dreadful. There's no public bathroom either btw.</p>

<p>Also, beware, a small cappuccino is really only one shot. They divide the
shots. When I saw that, I asked for the second. This annoyed me.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: cap tastes good despite mangled prep, bright and airy if you like that,
PASTRIES!<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: Inexperienced baristas, Split shots (who are you, Starbucks?), crappy wifi</p>

<p><strong>Final word</strong>: Beats Starbucks and the nearby Blue Spoon</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Macchiato, NYC]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-macchiato/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T13:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-macchiato</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.macchiatocafe.com/">Machiatto</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: near Times Square<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Macchiatto 44 roasted by Seattle-based Fonte Micro Roasters<br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: Fonte branded<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: unknown<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 12oz cardboard cups<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 8/29/2012</p>

<p>Sorry, no picture. This was on the run with friends.</p>

<p>Macchiato is a local two-shop chain in NY. It's a restaurant as well as coffee
bar and appears to have a brisk lunch crowd. Seating is small tables and
chairs. This was a spontaneous stop after having lunch with friends near Times
Square. We stood in a long but efficient line. I was alarmed at the amount of
milk they poured in my 12oz drink and thought it would taste more like milk
than coffee.  While I would have preferred less milk, the taste was still
sweet, I could still taste coffee and the micro foam was lovely.  The
temperature of the drink was fine without a sleeve and the taste was nicely
sweet, leading me to suspect they probably use local and/or premium milk.
I prefer my caps with less milk, but if you aren't picky about lattes vs caps,
you'll probably like it. If I'd actually ordered a macchiato, it probably would
have been lovely.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: Fast service, lovely taste, great micro foam<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: Busy and lacking in attention to detail.</p>

<p>Final word: I would go here if I were near but wouldn't go out of my way to get
some and I might look around for something different if I were planning ahead.
I think 12oz cups are way too big for most drinks, but it did taste good, so
YMMV.  It makes me interested in checking out Fonte Coffee Roasters in Seattle!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Blue Spoon]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-blue-spoon/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T09:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-blue-spoon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bluespooncoffee.com/">Blue Spoon</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, Downtown (Williams and Platt)<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Intelligentsia<br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: La Marzocco + Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: yes, from the park across the street (NY DTA), sketchy<br/>
<strong>Served In</strong>: 8oz cardboard<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 8/31/2012</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/bluespoon.jpg"></p>

<p>This is a small shop at corner of William and Platt in the Financial
District.  The coffee is too hot leading me to guess they overcook the milk. I ate
half a bagel waiting for it to cool off. If I had been walking, I would have
wanted a sleeve, which I generally never need with artisan coffee joints. It
was interesting that the beans were Intelligentsia as the taste seemed to
have a lot more licorice or citrus than the other locations serving the same
beans. Reminded me a bit of Stumptown when it's pulled too long.</p>

<p>Other, non-coffee specific: It's hot in here. It's a very small space and
I think there's some a/c near the counter, but I'm about 8 feet away at
a window bar and sweating while drinking my coffee. Also, despite ordering
"for here," I received cups with lids on them and a bagel toasted but wrapped
up in wax paper and a lunch bag.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: They're 2 blocks from where I'm staying and bagel noms.<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: scalded milk, bitter, citric taste, location heat.</p>

<p>Followup: It was 90 degrees Friday afternoon, so I opted to walk back here
despite the meh experience of the morning.  I got the same kind of drink that
I think had even more milk than my morning cups. Very disappointing
experience for a shop that actually has a La Marzocco in residence.</p>

<p>Final word: Despite the La Marzocco, this shop is not serving artisan coffee
and I don't recommend it. It beats Starbucks, but just barely. Intelligentsia
should investigate the crimes being committed against their beans in this location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Kaffe 1668]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/02/coffee-nerdery-kaffe-1668/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T17:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/02/coffee-nerdery-kaffe-1668</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://kaffe1668.com">Kaffe 1668</a></strong><br/>
<strong>Location:</strong> New York, Tribeca a few blocks from the GZ Memorial<br/>
<strong>Espresso:</strong> Intelligentsia <br/>
<strong>Hardware:</strong> Synesso &amp; Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art:</strong> Yes<br/>
<strong>WiFi:</strong> yes<br/>
<strong>Drink:</strong> skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Served in:</strong> 6oz ceramic cups<br/>
<strong>Visited:</strong> 2012 Aug30, Sep1 &amp; 3</p>

<p>  <img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/kaffe1668.jpg"/><br/>
 This coffee shop was recommended to me by a casual Facebook friend who moved to NYC
 from Minneapolis and used to be a barista himself.</p>

<p> Kaffe 1668 is a lovely little shop with dark wood tables and benches. It's
 quite dim inside and I really like it. They serve espresso drinks and
 individually brewed coffee.  My cappuccinos were low temperature and actually
 cooled rather quickly as I was lollygagging.  However, they were very good and
 I enjoyed every drop. In a world where too many drinks are made with scalded
 milk, I'm ok with the consequences of low temps. The shop has cold pastries.
 I had a scone on my first visit and a breakfast sandwich on a baguette on the
 next. The scone was good, the baguette was chewy(I know nothing about french
breads so take that fwiw).</p>

<p> Your wait for coffee can be significant. The line moved a bit slow and it
 took a while for my drinks to be made.  However, it's worth it as the
 baristas are perfectionists and won't serve a substandard drink. On my first
 visit I was informed that my second cup was late because they were remaking
 it.   I understand they recalibrate espresso pulls throughout the day here
 which is awesome.</p>

<p> One thing worth mentioning is that it seems to be a stroller destination on
 Saturday mornings. It's still worth it for good coffee which seems to be
 missing in most of Downtown, but cranky babies can be a bit tough on the ears
 in the early morning.</p>

<p> Bonus: They're open on Labor Day. Guess where I'm going when I get up
 tomorrow?</p>

<p> <img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/kaffe1668-2.jpg"/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
