<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blue ox | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/blue-ox/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-13T22:48:01-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Blue Ox, Minneapolis]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/15/coffee-nerdery-blue-ox/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T14:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/15/coffee-nerdery-blue-ox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://blueoxcoffeecompany.com">Blue Ox</a></strong><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: Chicago and 38th St, South Minneapolis, MN<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Counter Culture <br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: Mazzer and La Marzocco<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: Yes<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 6oz ceramic cups<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 2012 often</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/blueox.jpg"></p>

<p>The Blue Ox coffee shop opened up about 3 blocks from my house in 2011.  I love
them. I love that they opened up in what I consider a marginalized area of
Minneapolis, albeit one that people are working to revitalize. I love that
I can walk 3 blocks to get wonderful artisan coffee. Sadly, I'm super lazy and
often stay home and make my own substandard not-really-artisan coffee instead.</p>

<p>Blue Ox always has local art on the walls. Furnished with several second hand
dinette tables and chairs, they also have a comfy futon and you'll often find
the windows open and the ceiling fans running instead of a/c.</p>

<p>Baristas here are always willing to talk the finer points of espresso and
coffee with you.  They have individually brewed coffee, pour over and they'll
make you an AeroPress Aerobie coffee if you ask.  I've chatted with them and
I know they calibrate the espresso grind and length of the pull at least every
morning, sometimes more.</p>

<p>They've cycled through a few different brands of coffee and have recently
started serving Counter Culture beans. When paired with the local milk used
here, these produce a lovely, sweet  espresso drink.</p>

<p>Warning, Blue Ox only serves whole milk.  There is no skim or 2% here. They
probably have soy, although I haven't asked.  They have locally baked pastries
but no hot food. Today when I came in, they were also offering chips and hummus
or salsa.</p>

<p>When you combine the laid back atmosphere and super yummy coffee combined with
proximity to my house, Blue Ox pretty much wins my "favorite coffee shop in
Minneapolis" award.  That's not to say there aren't other places just as good
and I'll be getting to those in future posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
