<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blue Spoon | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/blue-spoon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-03T15:32:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Blue Spoon]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-blue-spoon/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T09:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-blue-spoon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bluespooncoffee.com/">Blue Spoon</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, Downtown (Williams and Platt)<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Intelligentsia<br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: La Marzocco + Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: yes, from the park across the street (NY DTA), sketchy<br/>
<strong>Served In</strong>: 8oz cardboard<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 8/31/2012</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/bluespoon.jpg"></p>

<p>This is a small shop at corner of William and Platt in the Financial
District.  The coffee is too hot leading me to guess they overcook the milk. I ate
half a bagel waiting for it to cool off. If I had been walking, I would have
wanted a sleeve, which I generally never need with artisan coffee joints. It
was interesting that the beans were Intelligentsia as the taste seemed to
have a lot more licorice or citrus than the other locations serving the same
beans. Reminded me a bit of Stumptown when it's pulled too long.</p>

<p>Other, non-coffee specific: It's hot in here. It's a very small space and
I think there's some a/c near the counter, but I'm about 8 feet away at
a window bar and sweating while drinking my coffee. Also, despite ordering
"for here," I received cups with lids on them and a bagel toasted but wrapped
up in wax paper and a lunch bag.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: They're 2 blocks from where I'm staying and bagel noms.<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: scalded milk, bitter, citric taste, location heat.</p>

<p>Followup: It was 90 degrees Friday afternoon, so I opted to walk back here
despite the meh experience of the morning.  I got the same kind of drink that
I think had even more milk than my morning cups. Very disappointing
experience for a shop that actually has a La Marzocco in residence.</p>

<p>Final word: Despite the La Marzocco, this shop is not serving artisan coffee
and I don't recommend it. It beats Starbucks, but just barely. Intelligentsia
should investigate the crimes being committed against their beans in this location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
