<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tribeca | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/tribeca/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-24T23:53:30-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Kaffe 1668]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/02/coffee-nerdery-kaffe-1668/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T17:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/02/coffee-nerdery-kaffe-1668</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://kaffe1668.com">Kaffe 1668</a></strong><br/>
<strong>Location:</strong> New York, Tribeca a few blocks from the GZ Memorial<br/>
<strong>Espresso:</strong> Intelligentsia <br/>
<strong>Hardware:</strong> Synesso &amp; Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art:</strong> Yes<br/>
<strong>WiFi:</strong> yes<br/>
<strong>Drink:</strong> skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Served in:</strong> 6oz ceramic cups<br/>
<strong>Visited:</strong> 2012 Aug30, Sep1 &amp; 3</p>

<p>  <img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/kaffe1668.jpg"/><br/>
 This coffee shop was recommended to me by a casual Facebook friend who moved to NYC
 from Minneapolis and used to be a barista himself.</p>

<p> Kaffe 1668 is a lovely little shop with dark wood tables and benches. It's
 quite dim inside and I really like it. They serve espresso drinks and
 individually brewed coffee.  My cappuccinos were low temperature and actually
 cooled rather quickly as I was lollygagging.  However, they were very good and
 I enjoyed every drop. In a world where too many drinks are made with scalded
 milk, I'm ok with the consequences of low temps. The shop has cold pastries.
 I had a scone on my first visit and a breakfast sandwich on a baguette on the
 next. The scone was good, the baguette was chewy(I know nothing about french
breads so take that fwiw).</p>

<p> Your wait for coffee can be significant. The line moved a bit slow and it
 took a while for my drinks to be made.  However, it's worth it as the
 baristas are perfectionists and won't serve a substandard drink. On my first
 visit I was informed that my second cup was late because they were remaking
 it.   I understand they recalibrate espresso pulls throughout the day here
 which is awesome.</p>

<p> One thing worth mentioning is that it seems to be a stroller destination on
 Saturday mornings. It's still worth it for good coffee which seems to be
 missing in most of Downtown, but cranky babies can be a bit tough on the ears
 in the early morning.</p>

<p> Bonus: They're open on Labor Day. Guess where I'm going when I get up
 tomorrow?</p>

<p> <img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/kaffe1668-2.jpg"/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
