<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Downtown | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/downtown/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-07T08:51:17-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Financier, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-financier/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T19:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-financier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://financierpastries.com/">Financier Coffee</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, Cedar &amp; William, Downtown, Financial District<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Financier (roasted in Park Slope, Brooklyn)<br/>
<strong>Machine</strong>: La Marzocco &amp; Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: kind of ("It's not working right now") <br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 8oz ceramic cups after I asked twice for "here"<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 9/2/2012</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/financiercoffee.jpg"></p>

<p>This drink had the potential to taste good.  Unfortunately the
barista had no concept of micro foam or craftsmanship. The taste is a little harsh but I can see
that it could taste awesome if prepared correctly.</p>

<p>Financier prepares and roasts their own beans and so I may come back again and
check as it has the advantage of being close to where I'm staying and the
subway stations are totally horked with construction this weekend. (n.b.
I didn't. I walked to Kaffe 1668 in search of a sure thing).</p>

<p>The pasty case looks amazing but I won't be able to report on that. The store
has long bar seating at the window plus some table in the back. While
I prefer the dark hipster coffee shops, this is still ok.  The music is kind
of pop/r&amp;b dreadful. There's no public bathroom either btw.</p>

<p>Also, beware, a small cappuccino is really only one shot. They divide the
shots. When I saw that, I asked for the second. This annoyed me.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: cap tastes good despite mangled prep, bright and airy if you like that,
PASTRIES!<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: Inexperienced baristas, Split shots (who are you, Starbucks?), crappy wifi</p>

<p><strong>Final word</strong>: Beats Starbucks and the nearby Blue Spoon</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
