<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: coffee nerdery | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/coffee-nerdery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-03T15:32:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Chromatic Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2013/03/07/coffee-nerdery-chromatic-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T08:19:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2013/03/07/coffee-nerdery-chromatic-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.chromaticcoffee.com">Chromatic Coffee</a>   <br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: Santa Clara, CA, a few miles from the Apple campus  <br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: <a href="http://www.chromaticcoffee.com/ProductDetails.asp?ProductCode=emperor%2Despresso">Emperor</a> <br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: La Marzocco and heavily modded grinders of unknown origin (see picture) <br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: heck yeah <br/>
<strong>Wifi</strong>: Yes <br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: Cappuccino <br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 5oz ceramic cups <br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: Daily in February and March 2013</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/chromatic_coffee.jpg"></p>

<p>I first met Chromatic Coffee when it was a franchise under another name in June 2012. For the record, it was super then too. I recently acquired a client in Santa Clara, CA and knew I would be traveling out here every week.  Strangely, Silicon Valley does NOT have a great artisan coffee shop on every corner. A lot of the area is actually office park and strip mall hell.  When I found this place last year, I drove 8 miles from the Hyatt Convention Hotel to get some decent coffee. (For the other record, all of the espresso served at the Hyatt is utterly vile).</p>

<p>So I immediately thought of this location when I set up weekly trips to California. In the meantime I discovered the shop had changed its name to Chromatic Coffee but was the same crew of awesome baristas that I'd met last year.  I actually managed to find a good hotel near the shop, putting me about 5 miles from the client but worth every commuting minute, knowing I'd have decent coffee at least once a day (I work in office park hell).</p>

<p>I am happy to say that breaking off on their own has only improved things over here.  In my chats with the baristas, I've learned that the owner is a tech obsessed uber coffee nerd. You can see this in the fact that they are their own roastery and hey, check out the grinders.  Heavily modded, the barista couldn't remember the original brand on them, but informed me that the owner is actually working on his own equipment as well. (uber techie coffee nerds unite!).</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/chromatic_grinders.jpg"></p>

<p>So I can't tell you enough how much I love Chromatic. Everyone there is super nice and super knowledgeable about the coffee and will happily nerd out over coffee talk when it's not busy.  There's also a Hario pourover bar and they tell me they make cold brew as well, which I will be sampling next week.  In addition to all the other awesome, they hold classes on everything from pour-over technique to barista art.</p>

<p>Bonus: They are not snooty coffee snobs here. You can order your drink with skim milk or to go and no one will look down their nose at your or inform you snottily that they only use whole milk from locally approved cows.</p>

<p>I wish I could keep gushing, but you should really get in here and try them for yourself. Don't be fooled by their strip mall exterior. They are beyond awesome.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/chromatic2.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Blue Ox, Minneapolis]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/15/coffee-nerdery-blue-ox/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T14:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/15/coffee-nerdery-blue-ox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://blueoxcoffeecompany.com">Blue Ox</a></strong><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: Chicago and 38th St, South Minneapolis, MN<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Counter Culture <br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: Mazzer and La Marzocco<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: Yes<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 6oz ceramic cups<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 2012 often</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/blueox.jpg"></p>

<p>The Blue Ox coffee shop opened up about 3 blocks from my house in 2011.  I love
them. I love that they opened up in what I consider a marginalized area of
Minneapolis, albeit one that people are working to revitalize. I love that
I can walk 3 blocks to get wonderful artisan coffee. Sadly, I'm super lazy and
often stay home and make my own substandard not-really-artisan coffee instead.</p>

<p>Blue Ox always has local art on the walls. Furnished with several second hand
dinette tables and chairs, they also have a comfy futon and you'll often find
the windows open and the ceiling fans running instead of a/c.</p>

<p>Baristas here are always willing to talk the finer points of espresso and
coffee with you.  They have individually brewed coffee, pour over and they'll
make you an AeroPress Aerobie coffee if you ask.  I've chatted with them and
I know they calibrate the espresso grind and length of the pull at least every
morning, sometimes more.</p>

<p>They've cycled through a few different brands of coffee and have recently
started serving Counter Culture beans. When paired with the local milk used
here, these produce a lovely, sweet  espresso drink.</p>

<p>Warning, Blue Ox only serves whole milk.  There is no skim or 2% here. They
probably have soy, although I haven't asked.  They have locally baked pastries
but no hot food. Today when I came in, they were also offering chips and hummus
or salsa.</p>

<p>When you combine the laid back atmosphere and super yummy coffee combined with
proximity to my house, Blue Ox pretty much wins my "favorite coffee shop in
Minneapolis" award.  That's not to say there aren't other places just as good
and I'll be getting to those in future posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Irving Farm, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-irving-farm/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T20:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-irving-farm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.irvingfarm.com/index.cfm">Irving Farm Coffee Roasters</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, 14th St &amp; 7th Ave, Uptownish<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Irving Farms<br/>
<strong>Machines</strong>: La Marzocco &amp; Doge<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: yes<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: Unknown<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 8oz ceramic cup<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cap<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 9/2/12</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/irvingfarm.jpg"/></p>

<p>Verdict: Noms. Seems like a lot of places in NYC are serving Intelligentsia
coffee.  While I don't object necessarily, it's nice to see a coffee shop using
locally roasted or even better, roasting its own.  My drink was mild and
reminded me a bit of Stumptown with it's citric tinge. They heated the milk
a bit more than some places but it was still drinkable and I like my milk with
a smidge of heat so the drink doesn't cool off too soon. I'm guessing they heat
to 145-150.</p>

<p>There are four small tables and a wall bench at this location, so the lounge
factor isn't high.  However, the was an elderly man enjoying his newspaper
when I got here and so I'm guessing foot traffic isn't too obnoxious.
The shop is small and unassuming from the outside and I wouldn't have noticed
except I got off the subway there and was looking for friends.</p>

<p>Fyi, no public bathroom</p>

<p><strong>Final Word</strong>: Noms.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Financier, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-financier/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T19:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/08/coffee-nerdery-financier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://financierpastries.com/">Financier Coffee</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, Cedar &amp; William, Downtown, Financial District<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Financier (roasted in Park Slope, Brooklyn)<br/>
<strong>Machine</strong>: La Marzocco &amp; Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: kind of ("It's not working right now") <br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 8oz ceramic cups after I asked twice for "here"<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 9/2/2012</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/images/financiercoffee.jpg"></p>

<p>This drink had the potential to taste good.  Unfortunately the
barista had no concept of micro foam or craftsmanship. The taste is a little harsh but I can see
that it could taste awesome if prepared correctly.</p>

<p>Financier prepares and roasts their own beans and so I may come back again and
check as it has the advantage of being close to where I'm staying and the
subway stations are totally horked with construction this weekend. (n.b.
I didn't. I walked to Kaffe 1668 in search of a sure thing).</p>

<p>The pasty case looks amazing but I won't be able to report on that. The store
has long bar seating at the window plus some table in the back. While
I prefer the dark hipster coffee shops, this is still ok.  The music is kind
of pop/r&amp;b dreadful. There's no public bathroom either btw.</p>

<p>Also, beware, a small cappuccino is really only one shot. They divide the
shots. When I saw that, I asked for the second. This annoyed me.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: cap tastes good despite mangled prep, bright and airy if you like that,
PASTRIES!<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: Inexperienced baristas, Split shots (who are you, Starbucks?), crappy wifi</p>

<p><strong>Final word</strong>: Beats Starbucks and the nearby Blue Spoon</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: La Colombe]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-la-colombe/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T19:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-la-colombe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lacolombe.com">La Colombe</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: New York, NoHo@400 Lafayette<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: La Colombe<br/>
<strong>Machines</strong>: La Marzocco &amp; Mazzer<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: yes<br/>
<strong>Wifi</strong>: unknown<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 8oz ceramic <br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cap<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 9/2/12</p>

<p>This was a quick stop while out shopping with a friend. There's ample seating
and it's a light, airy space. My coffee was ok, although it was a smidge
bitter. I'd probably have to try again to see how I liked the coffee.
However, it's a great place, good for meeting a friend or stopping in and
they take their coffee production pretty seriously. I didn't actually see
a menu anywhere although I wasn't looking.</p>

<p>They did have an adorable water "fountain" that offered room temperature,
cold or carbonated water and they'll offer you a water cup no problem.  The
staff is professional and fast. This coffee shop had the most starbucksian
feel to it of all the shops I've been too, but I don't really mean that in
a derogatory way. I just mean that they turned out product quickly. The
product they turned out was definitely far superior to anything Starbucks
will serve you. I still prefer low-lit, shabby, hipster joints, but I'd have
no problem coming back here.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: Fast, good coffee<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: None really</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
