<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nerds | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/nerds/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-11T08:36:14-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee for Traveling Nerds]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/01/coffee-for-traveling-nerds/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T09:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/01/coffee-for-traveling-nerds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm embarking on something I've wanted to do for a long time. Coffee reviews
for traveling nerds. I don't travel extensively but I do go places and my trip
logistics are often driven by my need for acceptable espresso drinks. Over the
years I've raised the bar several times for what I want in a coffee shop. I used to just get excited that
I could find Starbucks on road trips through Nebraska and Oklahoma or had
a Starbucks across the street from my hotel.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>These days I look a little harder for local shops serving artisan espresso
drinks. I have been know to pore over Google Maps and search the internet for
hours before choosing a hotel for a trip. For road trips I look ahead of time
at where we might be able to stop for coffee, mostly because I'm afraid we'll
miss the only coffee shop within 300 miles (this can happen in Texas!).</p>

<p>I'm not a top of the line coffee snob. I don't attend cuppings and I'm not sure
I could tell the diff between espresso shots. To be honest, I'm not too fond of
straight espresso. I prefer my drinks to be about cappuccino strength. I don't
roast my own beans although I've met those who have. I can't make very good
coffee art, although I enjoy trying.</p>

<p>I drink most of my espresso at home, which is part of what's raised the
bar when I look for coffee shops. If you spend a lot of time pursuing a great
shot, you start noticing when you're served bitter espresso or scalded milk. I went from religiously drinking
Caribou cappuccinos to actively loathing them over a period of a few years.</p>

<p>Many years ago I had a Krups pot boiler espresso machine and a blade grinder.
I used that for years and considered it fine. Then I started thinking I wanted
a nicer espresso maker and started reading.  That's when I learned about
grinders. Instead of buying a new espresso machine, I ended up buying a <a href="http://www.mazzer.com/scheda.asp?idprod=2">Mazzer
Mini</a>. This was before the Euro and when things were less expensive. I believe
it cost me around $350 at the time. That was all the money I could afford to
spend for a long time, so I had a super nice grinder and a crappy pot boiler
espresso machine.</p>

<p>Eventually my boyfriend and I each got Starbucks Barista machines on sale for
$200 and they were great for their price point until they died. At that point,
I was making more money and decided I wanted something nicer. I opted for
a <a href="http://www.rancilio.it/rancilio/prod_model.jsp?id_model=49&amp;id_language=3&amp;id_category=26">Rancilio Silivia</a>
which I later modded with a <a href="http://www.pidsilvia.com/">PID</a> that allows you to see and
regulate the brewing temperature for espresso.  This is where I'm at today:
Mazzer Mini, Rancilio Sivia. I tend to use the same espresso beans as
calibrating the grinder for different kinds requires wasting about half a pound
and too much time.  So I stick with a local provider: <a href="http://www.peacecoffee.com/">Peace Coffee
espresso beans</a>.
What do I consider an artisan shop? There are several optional
components but a few obvious things:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Their espresso machine aren't automatic</strong>:
If you push a button to make the espresso, chances are good it's going to taste
like ass, no matter how beautifully the beans were roasted. Example: I ended up
at a Pete's Coffee in Santa Clara and was surprised at how downright yummy my
latte tasted. This shop was using a La Marzocco. I was so pleased that when
I went to the airport, I ordered some there.  The same drink came out of an
automated machine and was so vile I threw it out.  Seriously.  So this one
isn't negotiable. You can't have an automatic and call yourself artisan. Please
point me in the direction of anyone making sublime drinks with an automatic if
you disagree.</li>
<li><strong>Beans are ground for each drink, not hours in advance</strong>:
Yes this really happens. I have stopped at a few places and had them make
espresso with grounds from a bin.</li>
<li><strong>Coffee Art</strong>:
I consider this mandatory although not necessarily every single time if I go
often. What this tells a first time visitor though is that your baristas have
been trained on more than how to look at a theromometer and push a button. It
also adds a nice finishing touch to the drink, communicating that each drink is
an individual effort.</li>
</ul>


<p>Less mandatory, I like it when the barista can talk about calibration and taste
notes with their espresso(s). Another thing you'll find in serious artisan
shops is milk snobbery.  When the Angry Catfish opened in Minneapolis, they did
several taste tests before settling on a local milk provider. They also only
serve whole milk, no arguments, although they'll also use soy.</p>

<p>So anyway, I've started writing up my NYC coffee shop experiences and will post
a separate snippet for each shop. I'll also create entries for places like that
awesome shop we found in Denton, TX and other recent trips to Baltimore,
Seattle and Santa Clara. I know this is
a technical blog, but coffee is so much a part of our lifestyles that it seems
a natural add-on. I hope you enjoy it and if you have suggestions for places
for me to visit, please let me know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
