<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Macchiato | Bratty Redhead]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/categories/macchiato/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-28T15:38:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sascha Bates]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Nerdery: Macchiato, NYC]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-macchiato/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T13:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.brattyredhead.com/blog/2012/09/03/coffee-nerdery-macchiato</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.macchiatocafe.com/">Machiatto</a><br/>
<strong>Location</strong>: near Times Square<br/>
<strong>Espresso</strong>: Macchiatto 44 roasted by Seattle-based Fonte Micro Roasters<br/>
<strong>Hardware</strong>: Fonte branded<br/>
<strong>Coffee Art</strong>: No<br/>
<strong>WiFi</strong>: unknown<br/>
<strong>Served in</strong>: 12oz cardboard cups<br/>
<strong>Drink</strong>: skim cappuccino<br/>
<strong>Visited</strong>: 8/29/2012</p>

<p>Sorry, no picture. This was on the run with friends.</p>

<p>Macchiato is a local two-shop chain in NY. It's a restaurant as well as coffee
bar and appears to have a brisk lunch crowd. Seating is small tables and
chairs. This was a spontaneous stop after having lunch with friends near Times
Square. We stood in a long but efficient line. I was alarmed at the amount of
milk they poured in my 12oz drink and thought it would taste more like milk
than coffee.  While I would have preferred less milk, the taste was still
sweet, I could still taste coffee and the micro foam was lovely.  The
temperature of the drink was fine without a sleeve and the taste was nicely
sweet, leading me to suspect they probably use local and/or premium milk.
I prefer my caps with less milk, but if you aren't picky about lattes vs caps,
you'll probably like it. If I'd actually ordered a macchiato, it probably would
have been lovely.</p>

<p><strong>Pros</strong>: Fast service, lovely taste, great micro foam<br/>
<strong>Cons</strong>: Busy and lacking in attention to detail.</p>

<p>Final word: I would go here if I were near but wouldn't go out of my way to get
some and I might look around for something different if I were planning ahead.
I think 12oz cups are way too big for most drinks, but it did taste good, so
YMMV.  It makes me interested in checking out Fonte Coffee Roasters in Seattle!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
